Two people meet in a park for the first time.
Cześć! Mam na imię Anna.
Cześć! Jestem Piotr.
Miło mi cię poznać.
Mnie też.
Then they say where they are from.
Jestem z Polski.
Jestem z Hiszpanii.
To ask a friend, or a child, their name:
Jak masz na imię?
This question is informal: for one person you know well, or a child.
Mam na imię Anna.
These three words, then your first name.
Jestem z Polski.
These two words, then the country.
The country name changes its ending, so for now, learn these as whole phrases.
Anna says hi and gives her name. What does she say?
Cześć! Mam na imię Anna.
Did you say it? Say it once more, out loud.
They shake hands. What does Anna say?
Miło mi cię poznać.
Did you say it? Say it once more, out loud.
Piotr is from Poland. What does he say?
Jestem z Polski.
Did you say it? Say it once more, out loud.
Now introduce yourself in the exercises below the video.